ニュースで学ぶ現代英語MCのトラウデン直美です
今回は竹下隆一郎さんに解説していただきます
竹下隆一郎ですよろしくお願いします
And I'm Tom Kane. Let's get to work on today's lesson
さあ今回は働き方に関する話題です
取り上げるのはNHK WORLD JAPANで9月17日に放送されたこちらです
Amazon requiring staff to work at office 5 days a week
アマゾンが従業員に週5日働くことを求める
アメリカのアマゾンが9月16日従業員に出社の頻度を週5日に戻すよう通達を出したというニュースです
まずはニュース全体を通して聞いてみます
US tech giant Amazon says starting January it is requiring its employees around the world to return to working at the office 5 days a week
CEO Andy Jassy sent a message to staff on Monday announcing
We've decided that we're going to return to being in the office the way we were before the onset of COVID
He explained the move was to deliver the absolute best for customers and the business
The decision reflects the company's view
Employees learn from each other and teams connect better working at the office compared to remotely
But the company is expected to face some resistance as
Some people have been working under the assumption they will be able to work remotely to some extent
Amazon employees worked remotely during the pandemic.
The company reviewed the practice last year and has since asked employees to work at the office three days a week.
Other big tech companies, including Google and Meta, are reportedly asking employees to work at the office two or three days a week.
では本文の内容を一文ずつ見ていきます。
US Tech Giant Amazon says
Starting January
It is requiring its employees around the world
to return to working at the office
5 days a week
US Tech Giant Amazon says
アメリカのIT大手の
アマゾンは述べています
Starting January
1月から
It is requiring its employees around the world
それつまり
同社は世界中の
それの従業員に
求めるつもりだと
オフィスで働くことに戻ることを
週に5日
CEO アンディ・ジャッシー スタッフにメッセージを送りました
アンディ・ジャシーCEOは従業員に通達を送りました
月曜日に
こう告知して
私たちは決定しました
私たちはオフィスにいることに戻ると
私たちがいたように
COVIDの発生前に
新型コロナウイルス感染症の始まりの前に
The onset of 何々は何々の開始始まりで
特に望ましくないことについて用いられます
He explained the move was to deliver the absolute best for customers and the business
He explained
彼は説明しました
The move was to deliver the absolute best
その動き決定は
この上なく最高のものをもたらすためでした
顧客と事業にとって
その決定は反映しています
その企業の見解を
employees learn from each other 従業員は互いに学び合うという
and teams connect better そしてチームはよりよくつながるという
working at the office オフィスで働く方が
compared to remotely リモートで働くことと比べて
but the company is expected to face some resistance
as some people have been working under the assumption
they will be able to work remotely to some extent
but しかし
the company is expected
その企業は予想されています
to face some resistance
いくらかの反対に直面することが
as some people have been working under the assumption
なぜなら一部の人々は想定のもとで動いているからです
They will be able to work remotely
彼らはリモートで働けるだろうという
to some extent
ある程度
Work under the assumptionは想定のもとで行動する
動くという表現です
Amazon employees worked remotely during the pandemic
Amazon employees worked remotely
Amazonの従業員はリモートで働きました
During the pandemic
あの感染症大流行 つまりコロナ禍の間
The company reviewed the practice last year
and has since asked employees to work at the office three days a week
The company reviewed the practice
その企業はそのやり方を見直しました
Last year
去年
and has since asked employees
そしてそれ以後従業員に要請しました
to work at the office
オフィスで働くことを
three days a week
週に3日
other big tech companies including google and meta
are reportedly asking employees to work at the office
two or three days a week
other big tech companies
他のIT大手企業
including google and meta
googleとメタを含む
are reportedly asking employees は報道によれば従業員に要請しています
to work at the office オフィスで働くこと
two or three days a week 週に2日か3日
それではニュース全体をもう一度通して聞いてみましょう
US tech giant Amazon says starting January it is requiring its employees around the world to return to working at the office five days a week
CEO Andy Jassy sent a message to staff on Monday announcing
We've decided that we're going to return to being in the office the way we were before the onset of COVID
He explained the move was to deliver the absolute best for customers and the business
The decision reflects the company's view.
Employees learn from each other and teams connect better working at the office compared to remotely.
But the company is expected to face some resistance as some people have been working under the assumption they will be able to work remotely to some extent.
Amazon employees worked remotely during the pandemic.
The company reviewed the practice last year and has since asked employees to work at the office three days a week.
このコーナーでは竹下さんとトムさんにリモートワークに賛成派と反対派の立場に仮に分かれていただいて英語で会話していただきます
お二人がどちらの立場でお話しされているかリスナーの皆さんも聞き取ってみてください
今回少し長くなりそうなんですけどまずはキーワードから一緒に頑張って聞いていきましょう
I definitely agree that there's been quite a bit of change, but I can't bring myself to embrace remote work completely.
If you're such a big supporter, let's hear why. Convince me.
Well, remote work isn't just about skipping the morning commute or staying in your pajamas all day.
It's about flexibility and productivity.
Flexibility? Sure, I'll give you that. But I don't know about productivity. Even if you do avoid your commute, it's impossible for me to imagine how the average person would be more productive at home or a cafe. I mean, you can basically do whatever you want, whenever you want.
熱いディスカッションが展開されていますがここまでの部分を一旦まとめてみますね
まず竹下さんがおっしゃってたのはここ数年でリモートワークは
つまり一時的な対策からずっと続くものに変化してきた変わってきたということでしたね
そして竹下さんは、A huge supporter of this changeという表現で、この変化を大いに支持していることを述べられました。
つまり竹下さんは賛成派だということがわかりますね。
はい、その通りです。私が賛成派でした。
トムさんの開始では、働き方に変化があったことにはアグリー、同意したけれど、
Embrace remote work completely
リモートワークを完全に受け入れるということはできないなと
反対派としての立場を取っておっしゃっていました
その後リモートワークに賛成する理由を挙げて
Convince me 納得させてみてというふうにもおっしゃってましたね
そう言われたので私も意地になってですね
リモートワークの良さは朝の通勤がなかったりとか
パジャマで1日家にいたりするということではなくて
だけじゃなくてIt's about flexibility and productivity
プロダクティビティ柔軟性と生産性があるということと言いました そしてトムさんの答えがフレキシビリティはわかるけどプロダクティビティはどうかな
ということでしたね カフェや家でどれだけ生産的に仕事ができるのかなぁということをおっしゃっていました
さあディスカッションの続きが気になりますね 竹下さんお願いします
はい
so when you work remotely you are in control of your environment
whether you are a person who thrives in the morning
or someone who hits their stride in the evening
remote work gives you the freedom to
最もプロダクティブな時期
I'll never say no to more family time. You're totally right.
But you might end up over-correcting and over-emphasizing the life side when everything is in your comfort zone.
リモートワークは、私が仕事をしなければなりません。
私は、仕事をしなければなりません。 私は、仕事をしなければなりません。
これは白熱してましたね すごく面白く聞き入ってしまいました
後半部分をまとめてみます
まず竹下さんはリモートワークでは環境をコントロールできるというふうにおっしゃいましたね
つまり朝にはかどる人 仕事特訓がはかどる人を言ってたんですよね
一方ですね someone who hits their stride in the evening は夜に本領を発揮する人です
リモートワークでは自分が一番生産的に働ける時間帯スケジュールを作れるということを言いました
この朝と夜っていう言い方も面白いなと思って聞いてました
あとトムさんは大学で教えられていた経験を話されて
リモートでの授業では悪夢のように散々だったというふうにおっしゃっていましたね
一方で私はそこで賛成派の意見として
リモートワークは健全な
Work-Life Balanceを持つことができると言いました
例えば通勤の電車とか
車の移動にかける時間を
家族と過ごしたり
自分の好きなことに回せるでしょう
ということを言いたかったんですね
トムさんはその意見を尊重しつつ
Life-Work Balanceの
ライフ側に偏っちゃうかもしれないね
ともおっしゃってましたね
そうですね
本当にトムさん粘ってきましたね
まさにここでなるほどなと思ったのは
リモートワークは理想的というにはほど遠いということでしたね
仕事用の服に着替えて家を出て人と顔を合わせて付き合うという環境の方が
気持ちを切り替えていい仕事ができるということをおっしゃってたんじゃないでしょうか
そこで最後に私はもう一度粘ってリモートワークに賛成だというスタンスで
技術の進歩によってもリモートワークの機会はますます広がっていくだろうということで締めました
最後の言葉すごくかっこよかったですよね
The future of work is changing
働き方の未来は変わりつつあるということでしたね
どうでしょうね私自身はきっと皆さんそうだとは思うんですけど
取り入れて必要な部分では使ったらいいというふうに思ってるんですけど
Yeah we have more freedom now so more options is always a good thing
ということで皆さんも英語でも日本語でもご意見を送っていただいて
リモートワーク賛成反対ちょっといろんな意見を聞いてみたいです
次回もお楽しみに
Keep up the good work
See you next time